Alexandros Filotheou

I have 7+ years of hands-on experience that includes SLAM, localisation, autonomous navigation, control, Computer Vision, and general integration and problem-solving. These I have acquired in real conditions with real robots as well as in simulation, working for research projects funded by the European Commission and the Greek State. I have mainly used ROS and ROS 2, but also MATLAB/Octave, all the while under Linux. My primary coding language is C++ and my secondary Python. I hold a PhD in Robotics and I am qualified with a Master's degree in Control and Robotics. I have deliberately chosen the academic + software engineering path because I wanted to reconcile the two dominant types of engineers: the academic type whose coding boundary is MATLAB, and the software engineering type whose boundary is code. It is my pleasure to document my motivation and contributions in a clear and concise manner that acknowledges my audience's existing knowledge with regard to code, presentations, technical papers, or tutorials. Most of all I enjoy being a member of a team and solving problems. Thank you for taking the time to read this.

Portfolio

Work Experience

2023.09 - present	Robotics Engineer Center for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH), Thessaloniki, Greece
2018.09 - 2023.03 [4.5Y]	Robotics Engineer ECE Department, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece
2016.09 – 2016.11 [3 mo]	Teaching Assistant · DD2380 Artificial Intelligence KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden
2011.10 - 2012.03 [6 mo] 2011.03 - 2011.05 [3 mo] 2008.07 - 2009.06 [1Y]	Database Designer · Egnatia Motorway S.A., Thessaloniki, Greece Application Developer (Int) · Egnatia Motorway S.A., Thessaloniki, Greece Telecommunications Engineer · OTE Group, Thessaloniki, Greece

Voluntary Experience

2013.10 – 2014.07 **Computer Vision Engineer**, PANDORA Robotics Team, Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Education

2018.09 – 2023.06

Doctorate

2005.09 – 2013.07

Diploma

Electrical and Computer Engineering Department
Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

2015.09 – 2017.06

Master of Science · Systems, Control, and Robotics
School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science
KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden

Computer and Other Skills

Languages C/C++, Python, shell, MATLAB/Octave, {PL/}SQL {Meta-}Operating Systems Linux, ROS 2, ROS
Tools git, OpenCV, Docker, Qt (cpp) | Tkinter (py), Behavior Trees, IATEX Control Techniques MPC

Languages

English Fluent — IELTS Score 8.5 (Greek Native)

References

Dr. Antonis Dimitriou · Coordinator of the projects for which I worked during my A.U.Th. years (+30) 697 88 96 350 | antodimi@auth.gr

contact: (+30) 693 87 87 677 | alexandros.filotheou@gmail.com source: https://github.com/li9i/cv